<?xml version="1.0" ?>

<directives>
	<directive>
		<id>time_format</id>
		<name>Time Format</name>
		<description>
			This format is the same as used by PHP's date() function
			and is used to format dates/times in output.
		</description>
		<type>string</type>
	</directive>
	<directive>
		<id>result_limit</id>
		<name>Result Limit</name>
		<description>
			This value is will be the number of content items shown
			on any page by Newsys. An example would be the number
			of latest headlines or stories to display.
		</description>
		<type>int</type>
	</directive>
	<directive>
		<id>page_limit</id>
		<name>Page Limit</name>
		<description>
			This value is used to determine the threshold of page
			jumping, i.e., the number of page links to show for
			output that spans multiple pages.
		</description>
		<type>int</type>
	</directive>
	<directive>
		<id>auth_type</id>
		<name>Authentication Type</name>
		<description>
			This value is used to determine which authentication
			type should be used to authenticate users. One of the
			following values can be used: `NEWSYS_AUTH_SESSION'
			for PHP sessions, `NEWSYS_AUTH_COOKIE' for HTTP cookies,
			or `NEWSYS_AUTH_HTTP' for HTTP authentication.
		</description>
		<type>int</type>
	</directive>
	<directive>
		<id>allow_comments</id>
		<name>Allow Comments</name>
		<description>
			Used to determine of any form of commenting is allowed.
		</description>
		<type>bool</type>
	</directive>
	<directive>
		<id>hier_comments</id>
		<name>Hierarchical Comments</name>
		<description>
			If true, this directive allows commenters to be able to
			comment to comments, thus allowing a hierarchical fashion
			of commenting as compared to the default one-dimension
			style.
		</description>
		<type>bool</type>
	</directive>
	<directive>
		<id>max_comments</id>
		<name>Maximum Number of Comments</name>
		<description>
			This directive limits the maximum number of total of times
			to which a story can be commented. When set to zero, no
			such limit is enforced.
		</description>
		<type>int</type>
	</directive>
	<directive>
		<id>use_rss</id>
		<name>Use RSS</name>
		<description>
			Whether or not rich site summaries should be automatically
			generated containing content from the latest stories.
		</description>
		<type>bool</type>
	</directive>
	<directive>
		<id>rss_icon</id>
		<name>RSS Icon</name>
		<description>
			The static URL to the rich site summary icon.
		</description>
		<type>string</type>
	</directive>
	<directive>
		<id>story_word_length</id>
		<name>Maximum Word Length</name>
		<description>
			The maximum number of run-on characters permitted in a
			story or comment before it is forced to be broken up.
		</description>
		<type>int</type>
	</directive>
	<directive>
		<id>story_auto_urls</id>
		<name>Automatic URLs</name>
		<description>
			If set, URLs are automatically turned into HTML hyperlinks
			from stories and comments, regardless if the anchor tag is
			allowed or not.
		</description>
		<type>bool</type>
	</directive>
	<directive>
		<id>story_auto_url_tlds</id>
		<name>Automatic URL TLDs</name>
		<description>
			A list of top-level domains should be specified here so
			text such as easyphp.net can be identified as a hyperlink
			yet at the same time excluding text such floating-point
			numbers and such.
		</description>
		<type>array</type>
	</directive>
	<directive>
		<id>story_allowed_html</id>
		<name>Allowed HTML</name>
		<description>
			A list of HTML tags names that will be permitted in posted
			stories and comments should be specifed here.
		</description>
		<type>array</type>
	</directive>
	<directive>
		<id>story_allowed_attr</id>
		<name>Allowed HTML attributes</name>
		<description>
			A list of HTML tag attribute values that will be permitted
			in the allowable HTML tags from posted stories and comments
			should be specified here. All attributes not in this list
			are stripped from the HTML tags they are found in.
		</description>
		<type>array</type>
	</directive>
	<directive>
		<id>story_attr_proto</id>
		<name>Protocol-checked HTML Attributes</name>
		<description>
			This list is used to determine which HTML tag attribute values
			should be checked for valid protocols.
		</description>
		<type>array</type>
	</directive>
	<directive>
		<id>story_allowed_proto</id>
		<name>Allowed Protocols</name>
		<description>
			This list is used to determine which protocols should be
			trusted. An example of a potentially malicious protocol, perhaps
			from an HTML image tag might be `javascript.'
		</description>
		<type>array</type>
	</directive>
	<directive>
		<id>allow_join</id>
		<name>Allow Anonymous Join</name>
		<description>
			This directive enables or disables users from signing themselves
			up as commenters.
		</description>
		<type>bool</type>
	</directive>
	<directive>
		<id>dbh_host</id>
		<name>Database Host</name>
		<description>
			The host of the database server used to store data.
		</description>
		<type>string</type>
	</directive>
	<directive>
		<id>dbh_username</id>
		<name>Database Username</name>
		<description>
			The username with which to log onto the database server.
		</description>
		<type>string</type>
	</directive>
	<directive>
		<id>dbh_password</id>
		<name>Database Password</name>
		<description>
			The password with which to log onto the database server.
		</description>
		<type>string</type>
	</directive>
	<directive>
		<id>dbh_type</id>
		<name>DBH Type</name>
		<description>
			The CPL DBH database type of the database server.
		</description>
		<type>string</type>
	</directive>
	<directive>
		<id>overview_break</id>
		<name>Overview Break</name>
		<description>
			This directive sets the value for the string to match while
			parsing a recently submitted story which will determine the
			value to use as that story's overview. This value will be
			removed from the story once the overview has been gathered.
			An example is setting it to the value `foo' and submitting
			a story consisting of the story content `overview foo story,'
			where the overview will consist of `overview' and the story
			content will actually instead be `overview story.'
		</description>
		<type>string</type>
	</directive>
	<directive>
		<id>of_type</id>
		<name>OF Type</name>
		<description>
			The CPL OF output format type to be used to format all output.
		</description>
		<type>string</type>
	</directive>
	<directive>
		<id>user_fields</id>
		<name>User Fields</name>
		<description>
			This directive allows for custom, user-defined (probably better
			described as administrator-defined) fields for the particular
			submission, being one of user information, comment, or a story.
			User-defined fields themselves consist of an identifier and
			corresponding array of values. Keys of the `user_fields' array
			should correspond to these field identifiers, which should be
			alpha-numeric in nature starting with a alphabetical character
			(note that the underscore `_' character is in this case
			considered an alphabetical character). The corresponding array
			should contain the following values: `name' corresponding with
			the field label, `type' corresponding with the basic type of
			the field, `database_type' corresponding with the database
			type definition of the field, `validation' corresponding to a
			Perl-compatible regular expression (with delimiters specified)
			to match a valid value for content entered into this field,
			`default_value' corresponding to the default value a field
			should contain, `required' corresponding to whether its value
			should be required for the story/comment/user to be submitted,
			`error_msg' corresponding to the error message that will be
			returned to the user when the `validation' field is not met,
			and `parse' corresponding to the type of data that will be
			expected, and how it should be parsed.
		</description>
		<type>array</type>
	</directive>
	<directive>
		<id>comment_fields</id>
		<name>Comment Fields</name>
		<description>
			Consult the `user_fields' directive.
		</description>
		<type>array</type>
	</directive>
	<directive>
		<id>story_fields</id>
		<name>Story Fields</name>
		<description>
			Consult the `user_fields' directive.
		</description>
		<type>array</type>
	</directive>
	<directive>
		<id>levels</id>
		<name>Privilege Levels</name>
		<description>
			This directive specifies labels for the various levels of
			privileges. An array specifying textular labels for these
			privilege levels should be specified. The currently defined
			privilege levels are `NEWSYS_COMMENTER,' `NEWSYS_REGULAR,'
			and `NEWSYS_ADMIN.'
		</description>
		<type>array</type>
	</directive>
	<directive>
		<id>sys_root</id>
		<name>System Root</name>
		<description>
			This value should correspond to the absolute location on
			server to the Web site's root directory from the system's
			point of view. For example,
			`http://www.box.com/~user/index.php' would point to the
			actual file `/home/user/htdocs/index.php' and this
			directive's value should be set to `/home/user/htdocs'.
			There must not be a trailing slash in this value.
		</description>
		<type>string</type>
	</directive>
	<directive>
		<id>web_root</id>
		<name>Web Root</name>
		<description>
			This value should correspond to the absolute location on
			the server to the Web site's root directory from the Web's
			point of view. For example,
			`http://www.box.com/~user/index.php' would point to the
			virtual file `/~user/index.php' and this directive's value
			would be `/~user'. There must not be a trailing slash in
			this value.
		</description>
		<type>string</type>
	</directive>
	<directive>
		<id>error_log</id>
		<name>Error Log</name>
		<description>
			If set, this file will attempt to be opened and appended to
			in the situation that an error occurs.
		</description>
		<type>string</type>
	</directive>
	<directive>
		<id>mail_errors</id>
		<name>Mail Errors</name>
		<description>
			If set, error messages will be mailed to the administrator
			according to the `admin_email' directive in the situation
			that an error occurs.
		</description>
		<type>bool</type>
	</directive>
	<directive>
		<id>show_errors</id>
		<name>Show Errors</name>
		<description>
			If set, error messages will be displayed on standard output,
			i.e., directly on the Web page. This is not recommended to be
			turned on in production environments.
		</description>
		<type>bool</type>
	</directive>
	<directive>
		<id>trigger_errors</id>
		<name>Trigger Errors</name>
		<description>
			If set, the PHP function trigger_error() will be invoked, thus
			enabling an administrator to define his own custom
			error-handling routines.
		</description>
		<type>bool</type>
	</directive>
	<directive>
		<id>xml_files</id>
		<name>XML_FILES</name>
		<description>
			This value should be an array of XML file type and location
			pairs. Currently defined keys for this value include
			`NEWSYS_XML_STORIES' corresponding to the absolute location
			on the server to the RSS data file.
		</description>
		<type>array</type>
	</directive>
	<directive>
		<id>path</id>
		<name>Path</name>
		<description>
			This value is used in two places, the first of which being
			the value relative to the Web site's root to the installation
			of Newsys from that of the Web's point of view and the second
			of which being the value from that of the system's point of
			view. An example would be `/newsys,' which is the location to
			the Newsys root directory for both the Web
			(`http://www.box.com/~user/newsys/stories.php' yielded from
			`http://www.box.com/~user,' the Web site root from the Web's
			point of view and `/newsys,' the Newsys root from the Web
			site's root) and the system (`/home/user/htdocs/newsys'
			yielded from `/home/user/htdocs,' the Web site root from the
			system's point of view and `/newsys,' the Newsys root from
			the Web site's root) with this directive holding the value
			`/newsys.' There currently is no way to distinguish the
			two uses for this value.
		</description>
		<type>string</type>
	</directive>
	<directive>
		<id>site_name</id>
		<name>Site Name</name>
		<description>
			This directive should hold the value of the name of the Web
			site.
		</description>
		<type>string</type>
	</directive>
	<directive>
		<id>site_uri</id>
		<name>Site URI</name>
		<description>
			This directive should hold the base address to the root of
			the Web site, for example `http://www.box.com/~user' or
			`http://www.box.com.' There must not be a trailing slash in
			this value.
		</description>
		<type>string</type>
	</directive>
	<directive>
		<id>site_email</id>
		<name>Site E-mail</name>
		<description>
			This directive should hold the administrator's e-mail address.
		</description>
		<type>string</type>
	</directive>
	<directive>
		<id>site_desc</id>
		<name>Site Description</name>
		<description>
			This directive should hold a description of the Web site on
			which Newsys is running which is used in situations such as
			RSS generation.
		</description>
		<type>string</type>
	</directive>
	<directive>
		<id>cache_dir</id>
		<name>Cache Directory</name>
		<description>
			This value should hold the absolute system path to Newsys'
			cache directory which it uses to save story and etc. output.
		</description>
		<type>string</type>
	</directive>
	<directive>
		<id>use_cache</id>
		<name>Use Cache</name>
		<description>
			Whether or not to use the cache and save the output of
			various operations that Newsys performs.
		</description>
		<type>bool</type>
	</directive>
	<directive>
		<id>templates_dir</id>
		<name>Templates Directory</name>
		<description>
			The absolute location on the Web server where the templates
			directory resides.
		</description>
		<type>string</type>
	</directive>
	<directive>
		<id>temp_dir</id>
		<name>Temporary Directory</name>
		<description>
			The absolute location on the Web server where the temporary
			directory resides which allows the user Newsys runs as to
			create, modify, and remove files within.
		</description>
		<type>string</type>
	</directive>
	<directive>
		<id>crypt_key</id>
		<name>Crypto Key</name>
		<description>
			This value should be automatically generated by Newsys
			during installation and should never need administrator
			modification, except perhaps in the case of a Newsys
			cloning or similiar. Its value is as a key to cryptographic
			functions to encrypt data in various places. This value
			should certainly not be made public.
		</description>
		<type>string</type>
	</directive>
</directives>
